As for areas where power consumption
is concentrated in this tower...
このタワー内で特に電力消費が激しいのは…２カ所ですね
There are two spots. One is around
the top floor, the other is the basement.
最上階付近と地下
I wonder which one
has what we're looking for.
どっちが本命かな
屋上近辺は電波塔ですからね
There's a radio tower on the rooftop,
so the large power consumption
there is to be expected.
そりゃ大量の電力消費も当然ですよ
However, even from here we can't
learn the details of the facilities below.
ところが下の施設はここからでさえ詳細が掴めない
The information display seems
to only show down to basement level 4.
案内表示では地下４階までしかないようだが…
But you know... the early blueprints
listed the basement as having twenty floors.
それがね　設計当初の図面だと 地下２０階まであるんですよ
This is fishy.
こいつはうさんくさい
Hm?
どうした
What's the matter?
An MWPSB vehicle
is already headed here.
もうこっちに公安局の車が向かってます
I bet it's Shinya Kogami.
That's not surprising.
きっと狡噛慎也だろう 驚かないよ
Let's split in two.
I'll go upstairs. You go downstairs.
二手に分かれよう
僕は上　君は下だ
Is it okay? Under the circumstances,
what we're looking for is...
いいんですか
この場合本命は…
Kogami will come after me.
狡噛は僕を狙ってくるだろう
If that's the case, it's more
sensible if I create a diversion.
なら　陽動を引き受けるのが合理的だ
チェ·グソン 君の働きに期待してるよ
Choe Gu-Sung,
I'm counting on you.
Understood. Please leave it to me.
分かりました　お任せを
Well... Seems like the party
is finally coming to its conclusion.
さて　パーティーもいよいよ大詰めか
I would like to show
Cut open my skull
Look into my head
I don't know why I'm so harsh
I could be so brash
I'm going to clash
'Cause I feel
I can always show
my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all again
'Cause I feel
I can always show
my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all
So it goes again
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:叶子 西西   校对:西西   时间轴:葛蔓 压制：娜夏
#16 The Gate to Judgment
Bingo. Shogo Makishima!
当たりだ　槙島聖護
What are you after in the
Ministry of Welfare's Nona Tower?
厚生省ノナタワーに何が目的だ
通報装置が遮断されています
The communications unit is cut off!
Hey, Shion.
おい　志恩
そっちはどう
How's it going over there?
It's about to become a war zone.
Is it possible to check the security cameras
これから修羅場だ
公安局からノナタワーの監視カメラをチェックできるか
in the Nona Tower
from the Public Safety Bureau?
The Ministry of Welfare is a
high-ranking organization, you know.
厚生省は一応上位組織なのよ
So you can't do it?
できないのか
If it's okay to use
the back door, I can do it,
裏口使っていいならできるけど
but I don't want to be
held responsible for this later.
後で責任問題とかになったりしたらヤダな
分かりました
Okay.
責任は全て私が取ります
I'll take full responsibility!
I recorded what she just said.
今の言葉記録しちゃったもんね
ＯＫ  裏口の鍵を使っちゃいましょう
Okay, I'll use the key to the back door.
次はギノに連絡だ　監視官
Next, we have to call Gino, Inspector.
So you're absolutely sure?
間違いないんだな
槙島かどうかは現在志恩さんが追跡中ですが
Shion is currently tracking them
to determine if it's Makishima or not...
but it's an unmistakable fact that
an armed group broke into the Nona Tower.
ノナタワーに武装集団が侵入したことは疑いようのない事実です
タワーは攻撃を受け 電子的通信的にも孤立しています
The Tower has been attacked
and has had its electronics
and communications isolated.
Considering how they
broke through the entrance,
エントランスを突破した状況を見ても
the security system
here can't handle this situation.
ここの警備システムではしのぎきれません
Understood. Inspector Tsunemori.
Also, can you hear me, Kogami, Kagari?
分かった…
常守監視官 あと聞こえてるか　狡噛と縢
Yep.
へーい
暴動はまだ続いている以上 タワーの方は俺たち一係で対応する
Since the riots haven't stopped yet,
we, Division 1, will deal
with the incident at the Tower.
Now, listen.
いいか もしも本当に槙島がいたら…
If Makishima is really there...
Capture Shogo Makishima.
「槙島聖護の身柄を確保しろ」
逮捕しろ
...arrest him.
We need to interrogate him.
尋問の必要がある
Make sure you capture him alive.
必ず生きたまま捕まえるんだ
I'll try.
努力してみる
Trying's not good enough!
努力するのは当然だろ
重要なのは結果だ
What's important is the result!
What's the matter?
どうしました
いや…ちょっとな
Well... Nothing really...
Should we wait for
Gino and the others to arrive?
ギノさんたちの到着待ちます
That's not funny.
冗談よせよ
I figured as much.
ですよね
でも　このタワーは３人で探索するには大き過ぎる
But this tower is too big
for the three of us to investigate.
大丈夫　俺たちにはすご腕の分析官が付いてる
It'll be fine.
We've got an expert analyst.
Yeah, the goddess of information analysis.
情報分析の女神さまが
Hey, that's me, isn't it?
ねぇねぇそれって私のことでしょ
そうかもな…
Maybe. So how's it going?
首尾は
I'm controlling all of Nona Tower's
security cameras from the MWPSB lab.
ノナタワーの全監視カメラを公安局ラボで制御中
敵は現在二手に分かれてる
The enemy is currently split in two groups.
Four upstairs, four downstairs.
上に４人　下に４人
Where's Makishima?
槙島は
He's upstairs. He just got
off the elevator at the top floor.
上　さっき最上階のエレベーターを降りたところ
Shogo Makishima
The top floor?
Not the government office floor?
最上階　官庁フロアではなく
Right. They went
straight to the antenna block.
ええ アンテナ区画に直行よ
I wonder if they're trying to
hijack the radio signal or something.
電波ジャックでもしようってのかしら
Their target isn't the Ministry of Welfare?
標的は厚生省じゃ…ない
What kind of men headed downstairs?
下に向かったのはどんな連中だ
Well... They went missing after they
went down to basement level 4.
それが…
地下４階まで降りたところで行方が分からないのよね
そっからメンテナンスハッチくぐって共同溝にでも入ったのかな
I wonder if they went
through the maintenance hatch
and entered a utility tunnel or something.
What the heck? That seems fishy.
何それ 気になるね
Let's go, Inspector.
We'll follow Makishima.
行くぞ監視官 槙島を追う
But what about downstairs?
でも下は
I'll go.
俺が行くよ
But then it'll be one versus four.
だけどそれじゃ１対４に…
It'll be two versus
four for you guys, too, right?
そっちだって２対４っしょ
Since Makishima's there,
wouldn't upstairs be more dangerous?
むしろ槙島がいる分 上の方がヤバいんじゃないの
Okay!
分かりました
- Kagari!
- Hm?
縢
Whatever you do,
don't act reckless!
無茶だけはすんな
I don't want you to tell me that, Ko!
コウちゃんにだけは言われたかねえよ
Analyst, can we use this elevator?
分析官 このエレベーター使えるか
It's locked so you can't use it. It's not
possible for me to unlock it from the lab.
ロックが掛けられてて使えない
ラボからじゃ解除は無理
- Dammit!
- What about the stairs?
クソッ
階段は
The enemy is on the 90th floor!
敵は地上９０階よ
Hold on a sec.
ちょっと待ってなさい
There it is!
見つけた
The control system for the
service elevators for transporting Drones
ドローン運搬に使う業務用特殊エレベーターの制御は
uses a separate system
from that of the Tower's center.
タワー中央とは別系統
現在も稼働中
They're still moving!
Give us directions.
ルートをナビしてくれ
Okay!
ＯＫ
Turn right at the hallway ahead.
その先の通路を右…
That's where I lost track of
them on the security camera videos.
監視カメラの映像で追跡できたのはそこまでよ
What's there?
何があるわけ
Well... according to the blueprints,
it's just a dead end.
それが…図面だとただの行き止まり
何かのワナかもしれない 気を付けて
It might be some sort of a trap. Be careful.
Yeah, yeah.
へい へい
What's that?
何あれ
Professor, the basement
should only have four floors, right?
先生　この地下フロアって４階で終わりのはずだよね
That's how it's supposed to be.
そのはずなんだけど…
I don't like this. This isn't for me.
嫌だな
俺　こういうの柄じゃねえのに
I really don't like this...
やめてくれよ
Shinya.
慎也君
I don't think you would,
but don't even think about using
まさかとは思うけど
ノナタワーのアンテナ塔で磁パルスグレネードを使おうなんて
the electromagnetic pulse grenades
near Nona Tower's antenna tower.
思わないでよね
If I do, Gino's gonna kill me later.
後でギノに殺されるからな
So how are you gonna deal with
those helmets the enemies are wearing?
じゃあ　敵のヘルメット対策　どうするつもり
If Akane goes with you,
you can't use the Dominators.
朱ちゃんが一緒だとドミネーターを封じられるわよ
That's why I picked one of them
up and brought it with me.
そのために わざわざ１個拾ってきたんだ
When someone's wearing this,
their Crime Coefficient can't be read.
こいつをかぶったやつの犯罪係数は 外部から読み取れなくなる
In other words,
if Inspector Tsunemori wears this,
つまり　常守監視官がこいつをかぶれば
they can't copy her
Psycho-Pass to their helmets.
敵のヘルメットにサイコパスをコピーされることもない
I see.
なるほどね
At any rate...
それにしても…
...what on Earth is Makishima after?
槙島の目的はいったい…
Makishima is a decoy.
槙島はおとりだ
The one who'll do the job is
probably headed to the basement.
たぶん本命は下に向かっている
そう考えなきゃ　この状況で敵が二手に分かれた説明がつかない
If that's not the case, them splitting in
two in this situation doesn't make sense.
There's a mysterious facility that
doesn't even have security cameras
地下に監視カメラもない よく分からない施設があるんだよな
in the basement, right?
Yeah, but the communication
from Shu stopped,
そうなんだけど…
秀君からの連絡も途絶えちゃってて
何がどうなってるのやら…
so I have no idea what's going on.
その施設の正体が槙島たちには何となくつかめているはずだ
Makishima and the others must
have some idea of what this facility really is.
Then... why...
じゃあ　何で…
Our priority isn't to stop
him from achieving his goal,
槙島の目的を阻止することよりも
but to drive him into a corner.
槙島本人を追い詰める方が優先だ
そうだろ
Right?
Hey, Professor, I'm telling you,
this place is really dangerous.
なあ先生 ここ絶対ヤバいって
I wanna go back now.
俺もう帰りて…
Professor?
先生
Communication error.
System link cannot be established.
「通信エラー」
「システムとのリンクを構築できません」
Hey, this isn't funny!
おいおいおいおい…
You damn bastard!
クソ野郎が
How's it going there?
Did you kill the guy?
そっちはどうだ 仕留めたか
Sorry, I turned the table on him.
残念　返り討ちだぜ
Oh my... Not bad...
おやおや…
やるもんだね
You're an Enforcer
from the MWPSB, right?
公安局の執行官だろ
何者だあんた
Who are you?
Why don't we have a little talk?
ちょっと話をしないか
This basement is a
large-scale anechoic chamber.
この地下は大規模な電波暗室になっててね
Only we, who are inside,
can communicate with each other.
中にいる俺たちしか通信はできないようになっている
You can no longer use
your Dominator, can you?
ドミネーターも使えなくなってるだろ
Even if an Inspector were there now,
you wouldn't have to worry about being shot.
今そこに監視官がいても撃たれる心配はない
No matter what you say or do,
there won't be any punishment.
何を喋り何を遣らかそうとお咎め無し
How does it feel...
どうだい　久しぶりに自由の身になった感想は
...to finally have your freedom again?
It wouldn't have been too bad,
if I wasn't in a cramped vault.
悪くねえわな こんな狭っ苦しい穴蔵じゃなけりゃ
Soon we'll have freedom in
the outside world, too.
もうじき外の世界でも俺たちは自由になれる
If we destroy the Sibyl System,
シビュラシステムをぶち壊してやれば
this crazy world will be
overturned from its very foundation.
このいかれた世界は根本からひっくり返るぜ
Hey, hey, are you serious?
おいおい　正気かあんた
This isn't a joke. Behind the
door that I'm facing right now,
笑い事じゃない
今の俺から扉一つ隔てた向こう側に
is the core of the Sibyl System.
シビュラシステムの中枢がある
What?!
You and I are the same.
We're latent criminals.
俺もあんたも同じ潜在犯だ
俺はネズミみたいにこそこそ隠れて暮らし
Just like a rat,
I live by sneaking and hiding,
and you're a disposable
hunting dog who has a collar put on.
あんたは首輪をはめられた使い捨ての猟犬だ
Hey, let me hear what you really think.
なあ　本音を聞かせてくれよ
How do you feel when you see those
who took everything away from us,
俺たちから何もかも奪い 虫けらみたいに扱ってきた連中が
those who treated us like scum,
killing each other all over town?
今街じゅうで殺し合ってるざまはどうだ
Don't you think it serves them right?
いい気味だと思わないか
ああ　まったく同感だね
Yeah, I completely agree.
To be honest, I was pleased.
正直胸がスッとしたよ
いつだってどこだって俺は人殺しのケダモノ扱いだった
No matter when or where,
I was treated as a killer beast.
But now, rather than me,
it's them who are the unsightly beasts.
それが今じゃやつらの方がよっぽどぶざまなケダモノだ
I wonder what goes through their mind
as their friends' blood splatters on them.
どんな気分で仲間の返り血を浴びてるのやら
Then...
だったら…
Don't get me wrong, you slimy bastard!
勘違いすんじゃねえよ ゲス野郎が
シビュラもクソだが てめえらもクソだ
Sibyl is crap, but you guys are crap, too.
他人をいいように踊らせて生かすの殺すの
Who do you think you are,
manipulating others and talking
about letting them live or killing them?!
何様のつもりだよ
If Sibyl is God, then are you pretending
to be the Devil or something?
シビュラが神様だってんなら てめえらは悪魔にでもなった気分か
バカ抜かせ
Don't make me laugh!
Both you and I are trash who simply
envy the happiness others have.
俺もあんたも他人の幸せがねたましいってだけのごみクズさ
このクソったれな街の市民さまどもが何千人と死んでこうがかまやしねえ
I don't care if thousands of citizens
in this damn town are going to die.
だがな　あいつらに殺し合いをやらせてるやつだけが
But I don't like the fact that only the
guys who're making them kill each other
のうのうと生きてるってのが気に食わねえんだよ
live carefree.
You should be the first to die!
まずてめえから真っ先に死ねよ
殺した数だけ繰り返し死んどけってんだよ
You should die over and over,
once for each person you killed!
You too have been killing
many latent criminals, right?
あんただって同じ潜在犯を何人も殺してきたんだろう
Enforcer, how many
times will you have to die?
執行官…あんたはいったい何度繰り返して死ねば済むんだい
Well, if there is really a hell the first
time I die, then I'm sure Yama will tell me.
まあ　一度死んだ先に地獄ってもんがあるんなら
そこで閻魔さまが教えてくれるんだろうさ
I thought we could become friends.
友達になれると思ったんだけどな
My friends are fighting your boss upstairs.
俺のダチは今上であんたのボスとやり合ってるよ
So I can't betray them.
だからこっちも不義理はできねえ
今すぐにでもあんたを殺しに行ってやる
I'm gonna go there to kill you right away.
Well, if you have enough time...
まあ　その前に間に合うようなら
...it'd be nice if you destroyed
Sibyl before I get there...
シビュラもぶっ壊してくれると助かるね
俺としちゃ世の中から気に食わないものが２つ同時に消えてなくなるわけだからな
...then, the two things I hate will
disappear from this world at the same time.
I'll try my best... although the security
on the last door is hard to crack.
善処しよう
最後の扉のセキュリティーが難物なんだけど
槙島は最上階の一番奥
Makishima is in the very back of the top floor!
By the emergency stairway!
非常階段の近く
There are no security cameras
around there, so I can't help you!
その周辺には監視カメラがないから援護できない
That info is more than enough!
そこまで分かりゃ　上等だよ
Crime Coefficient is 24.
「犯罪係数　２４執行対象ではありません」
Not a target for enforcement action.
What?!
Trigger will be locked.
監視官
Inspector?!
I'm okay.
大丈夫…
But why didn't the Dominator...
でも　何でドミネーターが…
How careless of me. Makishima's here.
うかつだったぜ ここには槙島がいる
His Psycho-Pass is
being copied to their helmets.
やつのサイコパスがこいつらのヘルメットにコピーされているんだ
So I was wearing
the helmet for nothing, huh?
ヘルメット　かぶり損でしたね
止血したら後を追います
Once I stop the bleeding, I'll catch up
with you. Please go on ahead!
先に行ってください
But you are...
でもあんたは…
Don't let Makishima get away!
This is an order!
槙島を逃がさないで
これは命令です
Shit!
You fought quite well,
considering your wounds.
その傷でよくやるもんだ
You are Shinya Kogami.
お前は狡噛慎也だ
You are Shogo Makishima!
お前は槙島聖護だ
Crime Coefficient is 0.
「犯罪係数　０」
"Justice is subject to dispute;
「正義は議論の種になるが 力は非常にはっきりしている」
might is easily
recognized and is not disputed.
「そのため　人は正義に力を与えることができなかった」
So we cannot give might to justice."
Sorry, but " I have long since learned,
as a measure of elementary hygiene,
悪いな　俺は
「誰かがパスカルを引用したら用心すべきだ」とかなり前に学んでいる
to be on guard when
anyone quotes Pascal."
I knew you'd say that.
That's Ortega, right?
そうくると思ってたよ
オルテガだな
もしも君がパスカルを引用したら
If you quoted Pascal,
やっぱり僕も同じ言葉を返しただろう
I would've said the
same words to you, too.
Us agreeing on something
doesn't really make me happy.
貴様と意見が合ったところでうれしくはないな
語り明かすのも楽しそうだが
It seems like it'd be fun
to talk the night away with you,
but unfortunately I'm busy
with other business right now.
あいにく今僕は他の用件で忙しい
That's not my problem.
I'll kill you right here, right now.
知ったことか
この場で殺してやる
刑事の言葉とは思えない
I can't believe those
words came from a detective.
お前に黒幕はいない
There isn't a string-puller behind you.
他の雑魚はお前に操られているだけだ
The other small fries are
just being manipulated by you.
事件の真相はお前を殺した後でゆっくり調べればいい
We can take time and investigate
the truth of the case after I kill you.
以前会ったとき 死にかけの君にとどめを刺すこともできたんだ
When I met you in the past,
you were dying,
so I could've finished you off then.
Don't you feel in debt
to me for letting you go?
見逃してあげた恩義を感じてくれないのか
Sorry, but you're going
to really regret doing that!
せいぜい後悔するこったな
Don't you want to know
the truth about the Sibyl System?!
シビュラシステムの正体が知りたくないのか
That can wait!
そんなものは後回しでいいんだよ
思っていたより拍子抜けの結末だが…
I had thought this would end
in a less disappointing manner...
それでも久々に退屈を忘れた
...but even so, for the first time in a long while,
I was able to forget my boredom.
感謝してるよ
I appreciate it.
Mr. Kogami!
狡噛さん
Inspector...
監視官…
Kill him.
殺せ…
Shogo Makishima.
槙島聖護…
You're... under arrest.
あなたを…逮捕します
What the hell is this?!
何なんだ　こりゃ…
こいつがシビュラシステムの正体だ
This is... the true form
of the Sibyl System!
この手でぶち壊すまでもねえ
We don't even have to destroy this.
こいつを世間に公表すればこの国はおしまいだ
If we make this public,
it'll be the end of this country.
今度こそ本当の暴動が起きる
And this time, real riots will occur.
No one will be able to stop them!
もう誰にも止められねえ
Target's Threat Judgment
has been updated.
「対象の脅威判定が更新されました」
Enforcement mode is Lethal Eliminator.
「執行モードリーサル·エリミネーター」
Aim carefully and eliminate the target.
「慎重に照準を定め 対象を排除してください」
Ch-Chief?!
きょ…局長
You are...
あんたは…
Enforcement mode
is Non-Lethal Paralyzer.
「執行モード ノンリーサル·パラライザー」
Aim calmly... and bring... the...
「落ち着いて…」
Oh, give me a break... This bites.
やってらんねえよ　クソが…
There's no way that I could love someone
But I want someone to love me
Even if yesterday could
continue unchanging into forever
You and I would never get anywhere
God... where did you go?
I don't hear any response,
but that's how it always is
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
I'll go with you
No matter the sin,
I'll bear the burden for you
I'll walk an uncharted path
All alone with you
A world where humans' state of mind and the tendency of their
personalities can be quantified. While all sorts of inclinations
are recorded and policed, these measured numbers
used to judge people's souls are commonly called "Psycho-Pass."
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations that appear in the show
are fictitious and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.